<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Gabi Surita</title><link href="gabisurita.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="gabisurita.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>gabisurita.github.io/</id><updated>2016-12-07T11:57:00-02:00</updated><entry><title>Just starting</title><link href="gabisurita.github.io/first.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-07T11:57:00-02:00</published><updated>2016-12-07T11:57:00-02:00</updated><author><name>Gabriela Surita</name></author><id>tag:,2016-12-07:gabisurita.github.io/first.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've always wanted to have a blog, but always used an excuse for not creating and updating it.
I've used to think that nobody was going to read it or what I did wasn't important enough.
Recently I've started to get involved with open software and specially Mozilla at project
called Outreachy (and was eventually accepted for it) and it's the first time that I feel
like I'm doing something really interesting and creative.
I hope I'll be able to log my experience here (and not give up this time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who don't know, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://wiki.gnome.org/Outreachy"&gt;Outreachy&lt;/a&gt; is a program that
organizes internships in free and open software companies for groups that are usually
underrepresented in these projects and computer science in general. Among the several companies
that are participating on this round, I've chose Mozilla to contribute to.
The project I'm most working is called &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.kinto-storage.org/"&gt;Kinto&lt;/a&gt;,
which is a self-hostable storage service over HTTP, with some cool features, like synchronisation
and sharing abilities. My main attribution during my 3 month internship is to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/Outreachy#Add_support_for_OpenAPI_to_Kinto"&gt;add support
for OpenAPI to Kinto&lt;/a&gt;.
I'll go through technical details on the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, thank you for your attention and I hope you'll enjoy the content. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="outreachy"></category></entry></feed>